<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Sportzz</string>
    <string name="latest_update_1">"After the mega auction in February this year, Cricket West Indies (CWI) basked in exalted glory that the players from the Caribbean were much sought after in the Indian Premier League (IPL). "The 17 West Indians make up the largest number of foreign players in the IPL, from any territory outside of India," the CWI had said a day after the auction.

        Its president Ricky Skerritt revelled in the demand for the Windies players. "This shows great faith in emerging West Indies talent. I continue to believe that our players can seek quality employment abroad, and still be positioned to operate constructively and successfully within the West Indies cricket system."

        Nine months on, the West Indies bubble in the IPL may have burst. Ten of those 17 players have been released and those retained were Shimron Hetmyer (RR), Alzarri Joseph (GT), Obed McCoy (RR) and Kyle Mayers (LSG) apart from Sunil Narine and Andre Russell, who were in the original retention list of Kolkata Knight Riders. Even the peerless Kieron Pollard has been dispensed with if one were allowed to say so -- for the record he has announced retirement from the league but he will play in other leagues. The same goes for Dwayne Bravo too.

        That may be the biggest takeaway from Tuesday's collective purge. The franchises' perceptible loss of faith in the West Indies players looks consistent with the popular discernment that the game may have passed West Indies cricket by. It also looks consistent with the team's recent performance, or the lack of it, in the T20 World Cup in Australia. A couple of days after the team's premature exit from the championship, CWI CEO Johnny Grave conceded in an interview that the West Indies team was lagging behind in terms of latest developments and changes in the game.

        Not too long ago the West Indies players, twice champions in the shortest version, were considered the exponents of T20 cricket. But conversations with IPL teams reveal now that an impression is fast developing in the league that the West Indies players are sticking to power play and may have not exactly adapted to the latest changes, styles and methods of the game. Some of those released may well be picked again, but the air of fear surrounding Pollard and Co may be fast eroding.

        The other West Indies players released on Tuesday were Sherfane Rutherford (RCB), Evin Lewis, Jason Holder ( both LSG), Dominic Drakes (GT), Odean Smith (PBKS), Dwayne Bravo (CSK), Nicholas Pooran, Romario Shephered (both SRH), and Fabian Allen (MI).

        The second big inference from the day's development is there has been a bid by the teams, barring Kolkata Knight Riders and Royals Challengers Bangalore, to create enough funds so that they can do some substantial transactions in the December 23 auction in Kochi.  "</string>

    <string name="latest_update_2">"Ben Stokes played the protagonist in yet another massive white-ball occasion for England as they beat Pakistan to win the T20 World Cup 2022 - their second title in the format. England bowlers gave a fine account of themselves after Jos Buttler won the toss to restrict Pakistan to just 137 for 8 at the MCG on Sunday (November 13) but their bowlers refused to bow out easily. Stokes however, broke away in the 16th over when England still needed 41 off 30 and violently turned the tide in England's favour with an undefeated 52.

About that over first...

Pakistan had done exceedingly well to bring the game down to 41 off 30, even putting England a run behind on par score as per DLS method, if it did come to that due to showers. It didn't, but the pressure was on Stokes and Moeen Ali as Shaheen Afridi returned to bowl. However, in the 13th over, Shaheen had hurt his knee while completing a catch to dismiss Harry Brook that made the situation a touch queasy for England.

Shaheen paid a heavy price for that effort however, as he walked off the field after struggling to deliver just one ball in the 16th over. Left-arm spinner Iftikhar Ahmed was tasked with completing the over, who was taken apart by Stokes for a four and six to finish off that reduced the equation to 28 off 24 balls. Moeen Ali further turned the tide by starting the next over - by Mohammad Wasim - with two fours, over cover and through square leg to force a collective drop of shoulders in the field.

Who gave the finishing touch?

Wasim dismissed Moeen but it came a little too late as Stokes achieved redemption for a forgettable evening in Kolkata from six years ago by hitting the winning runs on the last ball of the penultimate over.

How was the start to the chase?

With swing, seam and an MCG awakening...

Shaheen rocked the sea of green in the MCG stands out of their slumber following an underwhelming finish with the bat by cleaning up Alex Hales in the first over. Haris Rauf, with all his knowledge of the venue, then took out Phil Salt for cheap. If England had plans of another canter in chase, they had something else coming. There was an engaging tussle between Naseem Shah and Buttler, with the former consistently beating the outside edge of the England captain with late away movement. Babar Azam gave his quick a slip fielder too, but Buttler responded to that with a premeditated ramp shot over fine leg. England were on the verge of acing the PowerPlay despite the two wickets, until a peach from Rauf ensured Buttler ran out of luck outside the off stump. England ended the PowerPlay on 49 for 3.

The middle-overs tug-of-war...

Stokes took centrestage, but Pakistan came at him and the other batters with a renewed sense of hope and adrenaline after the early inroads made by the quicks. Shadab Khan, like Adil Rashid, got the ball to turn sharply and made run scoring tough through the middle overs. The scales were tantalisingly even for the next eight overs as boundaries came, but as did dot balls in clusters to ramp up the pressure. Babar even brought back Naseem, who continued to flirt with the outside edge, this time of Stokes. Stokes vs the bowlers became a staring contest where neither side blinked, until that 16th over.

About the first innings...

Initiation nerves for Pakistan

Stokes started the final with a no-ball and a wide but it was Pakistan who looked a bit groggy to begin with. The surface seemed a touch two-paced with value for change of pace, which England's quicks used extensively. Rizwan had seen enough early on, and went for a disdainful slog sweep against Chris Woakes in a 12-run fourth over, but dragged one on from Sam Curran just the next over. Pakistan limped to 39 for 1 in 6 overs.

Rashid the menace

The leggie had an impactful semifinal against India in Adelaide, and grabbed the bigger dimensions in MCG and the two-paced conditions with both hands. First ball, he had a visibly nervy Mohammad Haris looking to break away from his tetchy start, and tossed one up to him. The youngster fell for it and danced down, only to not connect well enough to clear Stokes at long on.

Buttler tried to go the semifinal way, by squeezing in an over or two from Liam Livingstone, but Shan Masood saw right through it and went after him - hitting a six down the ground in a 16-run over. Rashid then came back and dented Pakistan again, with a raging googly that turned too sharply and caught Babar by surprise. The Pakistan skipper awkwardly got his bat to the ball, only to hit it straight back to the bowler. He then bowled five dots, repeatedly beating Iftikhar Ahmed's outside edge with prodigious away turn.

A six-ball duck and a Shadab-Masood fuelled recovery

Stokes made the most of the excess MCG bounce, and sent Iftikhar packing with a length ball that he edged to Buttler. Pakistan were on thin ice at 85 for 4 in the 13th over but Masood combined with Shadab to plot Pakistan's late recovery. The pair added 35 quick runs in the next four overs to set Pakistan up for a big finish.

Curran, Jordan hit the brakes

The game had started to gravitate towards Pakistan but the fast bowling duo duly snatched it back to their corner, with hard lengths and slower ones. Masood mistimed a pull off Curran, and hit straight to Livingstone at deep midwicket while Shadab's cross-batted hit against Jordan's short ball went only as far as Stokes at mid-off in the following over. Pakistan were down to 123 for 6 in the 18th over, and ended up adding just 14 more to their total. Curran, who went on to dismiss Mohammad Nawaz too, finished with exceptional figures of 3 for 12, including 15 dot balls.

Brief Scores: Pakistan 137/8 in 20 overs (Shan Masood 38, Babar Azam 32; Sam Curran 3-12, Adil Rashid 2-22, Chris Jordan 2-27) lost to England 138/5 in 19 overs (Ben Stokes 52*, Jos Buttler 26; Haris Rauf 2-23) by 5 wickets."</string>
    <string name="title_activity_recent_update1">recent_update1</string>
    <!-- Strings used for fragments for navigation -->
    <string name="first_fragment_label">First Fragment</string>
    <string name="second_fragment_label">Second Fragment</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="previous">Previous</string>

    <string name="hello_first_fragment">Hello first fragment</string>
    <string name="hello_second_fragment">Hello second fragment. Arg: %1$s</string>
    <string name="choose_theme_text">choose_theme_text</string>

    <string name="india_new">"Hardik Pandya and the new-look India's fresh start was supposed to take off at Wellington but persistent rain meant that the clash of the losing semi-finalists of the T20 World Cup was reduced to a two-match series. Chances of the series being further abridged is a possibility as rain threat looms large over Mount Maunganui too.

Pandya has already led the team three times, twice against Ireland and once against the West Indies, but this series was supposed to herald a new direction for India in the T20I format. A couple of matches against New Zealand would serve as a good starting point to see how the players respond under Pandya's leadership, their approach to the game, how they react to pressure, etc. But beyond all that, they will first hope that the weather stays clear.

In the New Zealand camp, the focus will be on their leader Kane Williamson, who has been in the news a lot of late. There were strike rate issues that kept emerging during the multi-team event in Australia while he was also one of the big releases in the IPL just nine months after being the first player to be retained by Sunrisers Hyderabad. He will be keen to put that all behind him and focus on what's in front of him, as will the rest of the New Zealand players.

When: Sunday, November 20 at 7:30 PM Local Time (12:00 PM IST)

Where: Bay Oval, Mount Maunganui

What to expect: Thunderstorms are forecast on the match day and could lead to a curtailed game or even a complete washout. Teams batting first have won all T20Is at this venue.

Team News:

New Zealand: The impressive Finn Allen should get another opportunity at the top of the order with Martin Guptill being left out of the squad. Barring Trent Boult's absence, the team should resemble the setup that featured in the T20 World Cup.

Probable XI: Finn Allen, Devon Conway, Kane Williamson, Glenn Phillips, Daryl Mitchell, James Neesham, Mitchell Santner, Tim Southee, Ish Sodhi, Adam Milne, Lockie Ferguson.

India: Rishabh Pant should get to play with Dinesh Karthik not picked for this series. But it remains to be seen if he bats at the top of the order. Yuzvendra Chahal, who went without a game in the T20 World Cup, should get in too in the absence of R Ashwin.

Probable XI: Shubman Gill, Ishan Kishan, Shreyas Iyer / Sanju Samson / Deepak Hooda, Suryakumar Yadav, Rishabh Pant, Hardik Pandya, Washington Sundar, Bhuvneshwar Kumar, Umran Malik / Harshal Patel, Yuzvendra Chahal, Arshdeep Singh.

Did you know?

- Mitchell Santner has dismissed Sanju Samson twice in the seven balls he has bowled to him in this format

- Suryakumar Yadav's tally of 1040 runs is only the second instance of a batter scoring 1000-plus runs in a calendar year

- Bhuvneshwar Kumar has picked 36 T20I wickets this year - only two bowlers have a better tally

What they said:

"I think it will be very interesting to see where they bat Rishabh Pant. Big question for Team India is how they will be using Rishabh Pant and I think we will be seeing him at the top of the order and trying to give him enough balls to showcase his skills. He is second to none when it comes to stroke play and has baffled a lot of international bowlers of high pedigree. We need to embrace the fact that there will be a few failures from him, but when he gets going, he is a terrific player to watch" - Dinesh Karthik "</string>
</resources>